<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>USD MS-ADS</title>
    <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content on USD MS-ADS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://usd-msads.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      FALL 2020 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science Sep. 8, 2020 Oct. 26, 2020    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming Oct. 27, 2020 Dec. 14, 2020    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum   Course Units Course Title Topics Covered     Foundation ADS 500A  3 Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science Statistical ConceptsProbability Theory, Random and Multivariate VariablesData and Sampling DistributionsDescriptive StatisticsHypothesis Testing    ADS 500B 3 Prerequisite - Data Science Programming Data Structures and AlgorithmsIntroduction to Python and R ProgrammingAdvanced Python and R Data Analytics Programming    ADS 501 3 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics Data Science Methods Introductory and VisualizationAnalytics Problem SolvingBig Data ConceptsData Ethics    ADS 502 3 Applied Data Mining Data Types and PreprocessingClassification Concepts and TechniquesCluster Analysis Concepts and AlgorithmsAssociation Analysis Concepts and AlgorithmsAnomaly Detection   Core ADS 503 3 Applied Predictive Modeling Practical Data Preprocessing with Linear, Nonlinear,Tree-based and Rule-Based Models for Regression andClassification Problems in Python and R    ADS 504 3 Machine Learning and Deep Learning for Data Science Supervised, Unsupervised, Reinforcement LearningNeural NetworksFundamentals of Deep Learning    ADS 505 3 Applied Data Science for Business Applications of Data Science in Marketing and FinanceSWOT AnalysisResearch Course TopicPost-processing Modeling    ADS 506 3 Applied Time Series Analysis Time Series Regression and Exploratory Data AnalysisSeasonality/Stationarity, MARS, ARMA, ARIMA, VAR Models    ADS 507 3 Practical Data Engineering SQLSparkRelational AlgebraReading and Writing Tables Database Modeling    ADS 508 3 Data Science with Cloud Computing Cloud Computing FoundationsAmazon Web Services (AWS)Distributed ComputingWorking with Cloud Services and Platforms    ADS 509 2 Applied Text Mining Parsing and Preprocessing TextTopic Modeling and ClusteringText ClassificationSentiment Analysis   Capstone ADS 599A 1 Capstone Project I Data AcquisitionData CleaningPreprocessingFeature Engineering    ADS 599B 3 Capstone Project II Data ModelingModel Deployment and Interpretation Report    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/fall2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/fall2021/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      FALL 2021 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science Sept. 7, 2021 Oct. 25, 2021    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming Oct. 26, 2021 Dec. 13, 2021    ADS 501 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics Sept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/faq/</guid>
      <description>Is GRE or GMAT required for admission?
Applicants with a GPA above 2.5 are not required to take GRE or GMAT. For applicants whose GPA is between 2.0 and 2.5, a GRE or GMAT will be required.
Do I need an undergraduate degree related to science or engineering to apply for MS-ADS at USD?
Even though it is expected that applicants acquire their bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in any STEM field (science, technology, engineering or mathematics), the program is also open to those with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree from any other field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/rankings/</guid>
      <description>RankingsThe University of San Diego, established in 1949, is a highly rated private, Catholic university that regularly earns accolades and honors from academic websites and publications. USD citations include:
The Princeton Review
#6 Most Beautiful Campus#8 Best Quality of Life#14 Most Popular Study Abroad Program#17 Best-run Colleges#24 Top 50 Green CollegesU.S. News &amp;amp; World Report
#13 Best Undergraduate Engineering Programs#19 Best Online Graduate Criminal Justice Programs#56 Best Colleges for Veterans#63 Best Value Schools#88 National Universities#90 Best Business Programs#97 Best Undergraduate Business ProgramsBusiness Insider</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/spring2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/spring2021/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      SPRING 2021 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science Jan. 12, 2021 March 1, 2021    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming March 2, 2021 April 19, 2021    ADS 501 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics Jan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/spring2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/spring2022/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      SPRING 2022 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science TBD TBD    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming TBD TBD    ADS 501 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics TBD TBD    ADS 502 Applied Data Mining TBD TBD   Core ADS 507 Practical Data Engineering TBD TBD    ADS 508 Data Science with Cloud Computing TBD TBD    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/summer2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/summer2021/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      SUMMER 2021 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science May 11, 2021 June 28, 2021    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming June 29, 2021 Aug. 16, 2021    ADS 501 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics May 11, 2021 June 28, 2021    ADS 502 Applied Data Mining June 29, 2021 Aug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/summer2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://usd-msads.github.io/about/summer2022/</guid>
      <description>Calendar  FALL 2020 SPRING 2021 SUMMER 2021 FALL 2021 SPRING 2022 SUMMER 2022      SUMMER 2022 Course Number Course Title Start Date End Date     Foundation ADS 500A Prerequisite - Probability and Statistics for Data Science TBD TBD    ADS 500B Prerequisite - Data Science Programming TBD TBD    ADS 501 Foundations of Data Science and Data Ethics TBD TBD    ADS 502 Applied Data Mining TBD TBD   Core ADS 503 Applied Predictive Modeling TBD TBD    ADS 504 Machine Learning and Deep Learning for Data Science TBD TBD   Core/Capstone ADS 509 Applied Text Mining (2 credit units) TBD TBD    ADS 599A Capstone Project I (1 credit unit) TBD TBD    ADS 599B Capstone Project II (3 credit units) TBD TBD    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
